You say you want a revolution?
Spice World is a adventure, fantasy, drama film directed by Bob Spiers.
World famous pop group the Spice Girls zip around London in their luxurious double
decker tour bus having various adventures and performing for their fans.
Victoria - Posh Spice, played by Victoria Beckham.
Melanie B - Scary Spice, played by Mel B.
Emma - Baby Spice, played by Emma Bunton.
Melanie C - Sporty Spice, played by Melanie C.
Geri - Ginger Spice, played by Geri Halliwell-Horner.
Clifford, played by Richard E. Grant.
Spice World is a 1997 British musical comedy film directed
by Bob Spiers and written by Kim Fuller.
The film stars pop girl group the Spice Girls, who all play themselves.
The film — made in a similar vein to the Beatles' 1964 film A Hard Day's Night — depicts a series of fictional events leading up to a major concert at London's Royal Albert Hall, liberally interspersed with dream sequences and flashbacks as
well as surreal moments and humorous asides, whilst also including a subplot dealing with a smear campaign against the Spice Girls by an overzealous newspaper CEO in an attempt to destroy their reputation for his own benefit.
This is the second feature-length film directed by
Spiers, following That Darn Cat (1997).
The film features Richard E.
Grant, Alan Cumming, George Wendt, Claire Rushbrook, Mark McKinney and Roger Moore in
supporting roles, with cameo appearances by a number of British celebrities.
Filming took place in London for six of the eight filming weeks and also inside
Twickenham Studios, as well as at over forty famous British landmarks.
Shooting featured several fourteen-hour shooting sessions and a constant,
heavy media presence due to the Spice Girls' popularity.
The film premiered in the United Kingdom on 15 December 1997, ahead of its wide
theatrical release on the British holiday Boxing Day (26 December).
In North America, it was released on 23 January 1998 by Columbia Pictures.
In the United States, Spice World became a box office success and broke the record for the
highest-ever weekend debut for Super Bowl weekend with box office sales of $10.5 million.
The film grossed $56 million at the worldwide box office and received primarily negative reviews
for its lack of cohesive plot, poor acting performances and uninspired humour.
To celebrate its 20th anniversary in 2017, Spice World was given a limited
re-release across the United Kingdom showing at Odeon Cinemas.
Spice World is the highest-grossing film of all time by a musical group.
It has arguably achieved cult status.
The film explores themes of media, pop star, manager, pop, bus.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and mind_bending.